<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./Smartsviewer2_icon.png" type="Manipulator">
    <name>SMARTSViewer</name>
    
    <shortDescription>
        Retrieves a SMARTSViewer visualisation of a columns of SMARTS strings using the service at www.smartsviewer.de
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>Provides a <a href="http://http://smartsview.zbh.uni-hamburg.de/">SMARTSviewer</a> visualisation
        of a column of SMARTs strings 
        using the service provided by the University of Hamburg.  The node performs no validation
        of the SMARTs strings prior to sending to the webservice. For more detailed information 
        about the implementation see either the Help file at <a href="http://smartsview.zbh.uni-hamburg.de/smartsview/view">http://smartsview.zbh.uni-hamburg.de/smartsview/view</a>
        or the following reference: <br />
        K. Schomburg, H.-C. Ehrlich, K. Stierand, M.Rarey; 
        <a href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/ci100209a">From Structure Diagrams to Visual Chemical Patterns</a>, <i>J. Chem. Inf. Model.</i>, 2010, <b>50</b>, pp 1529-1535
		
		<p>
		The <i>Communication Error Settings</i> tab allows setting of behaviour relating to server communication problem handling. 
		The values set are applied to each row in turn.  The server will only be contacted until a successful result is returned. 
		The settings allow the user to control the behaviour of the node should the SMARTSviewer server be functioning incorrectly. 
		<i>Note</i> that it is not currently possible to cancel execution during a row, so use long delay settings with care!
		</p>
		<p><i>
		Note that SMARTs strings are transferred to the remote server unencrypted, and the the server
        maintains an anonymous record of query SMARTs strings to aid future development.</i></p>
		<p>This node was developed by <a href="http://www.vernalis.com/">Vernalis (Cambridge, UK)</a>.
		For feedback and more information, please contact <a href="mailto:knime@vernalis.com">knime@vernalis.com</a>
		</p>
        </intro>
        
        <tab name="Options">
        <option name="Select a column containing the SMARTs Strings">Select a column containing SMARTs strings for visualsation.  
        No SMARTS validation is carried out prior to sending to the remote server, which will
        return a blank image for invalid SMARTS strings</option>
        <option name="Select legend type">Choose the desired legend type: Dynamic - detailed text description of each atom and bond;
         Static - short description of how each symbol is depicted in the visualisation</option>
        <option name="Select Visualisation modus">Element symbols uses text representation of the element symbols in the depiction</option>
        </tab>
        
        <tab name="Communication Error Settings">
            <option name="Number of retries to contact server">Set the number of times the server will be re-contacted following a failure.</option>
            <option name="Delay between attempts (secs)">The delay period between each re-try</option>
            <option name="Ignore server errors">If set, the node will return a 'missing value' cell for each row which failed to contact the server after the
            defined number of attempts - allowing workflow execution to continue, otherwise node execution will fail.  
            Setting a long delay interval (max 10 minutes) and large number of attempts
            (max 20) allows the workflow a chance to restore functionality (it will take over 3 hours between the first and last attempt for each row in these circumstances)</option>
            <option name="Restore Defaults">Restore the default server settings.</option>
        </tab>

    </fullDescription>
    
    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="In port 0">Input port containing a column of SMARTS strings, either as String, SMARTS or Smiles format</inPort>
        <!-- possibly more input ports here-->
        <outPort index="0" name="Appended SMARTSViewer Renderings">The input table with the SMARTSViewer representations appended as a PNG column</outPort>
        <!-- possibly more output ports here-->
    </ports>    
    <!--<views>
        <view index="0" name="name of first view">Description of first view...</view>
    </views>-->
</knimeNode>
