<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!--
  Copyright (c) 2019, Vernalis (R&D) Ltd
   This program is free software; you can redistribute it and/or modify it 
   under the terms of the GNU General Public License, Version 3, as 
   published by the Free Software Foundation.
   
   This program is distributed in the hope that it will be useful, but 
   WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY; without even the implied warranty of 
   MERCHANTABILITY or FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE. 
   See the GNU General Public License for more details.
    
   You should have received a copy of the GNU General Public License
   along with this program; if not, see <http://www.gnu.org/licenses>
-->
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode
	icon="boxplot.png"
	type="Visualizer">
	<name>Notched Boxplot (JFreechart)</name>

	<shortDescription>
		Node to generate notched boxplots.
	</shortDescription>

	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
			This node generates notched boxplots of categorical data.
			<p>
				The boxplot shows the following:
				<ul>
					<li>The box shows the interquartile range (IQR; Q1 to Q3)</li>
					<li>The whiskers show the extent of the 'regular' values - i.e the
						range of the actual values within 1.5 * IQR of the IQR
					</li>
					<li>The mean is shown as an open circle with a cross in, which may
						or may not be
						within the box
					</li>
					<li>The median is shown as a line crossing the box</li>
					<li>
						The notch shows the 95% confidence interval of the median,
						defined
						as +/- 1.57 * IQR / sqrt(N), where N is the number of
						values. The notch is centred on the median,
						and may extend beyond
						the ends of the boxes
					</li>
					<li>Outliers are shown as 'o' beyond the whiskers. Outliers are in
						the range 1.5 * IQR to 2 * IQR beyond the IQR
					</li>
					<li>Extreme outliers are shown as 'x' beyond the whiskers. Outliers
						are beyond 2* IQR beyond the IQR
					</li>
				</ul>
				See
				<a
					href="https://sites.google.com/site/davidsstatistics/home/notched-box-plots">this page</a>
				for details and references
			</p>


			The chart is coloured as follows:
			<p>
				If the 2nd Port is null, then the colour is as follows.
				<ul>
					<li>The outline and whisker are the specified default outline
						colour
					</li>
					<li>If there is a ColorModel on the 1st port for the category
						column,
						then the fill is from the colour model
					</li>
					<li>If no colormodel, or it is not on the category column, then the
						fill colour is the specified default fill colour
					</li>
				</ul>

			</p>
			<p>
				If the 2nd port is connected, then it must contain a single string
				column
				with a colour model associated to it. The column must contain
				the names
				of the series columns (Using an Extract Column Header ->
				Transpose -> Color Manager sequence of nodes achieves this). Now,
				the colouring is as follows:
			</p>

			<p>
				<i>Outline &amp; Whisker</i>
				<ul>
					<li>If there is a ColorModel on the 1st port for the category
						column,
						then the outline is from the colour model
					</li>
					<li>If no colormodel, or it is not on the category column, then the
						outline is the default outline colour specified
					</li>
				</ul>
			</p>
			<p>
				<i>Fill</i>
				<ul>
					<li>If there is a single StringCell column in the second table,
						then the
						series fill colours come from the color model
					</li>
					<li>If not, or for series names not represented, the fill colour is
						the default fill colour specified.
					</li>
				</ul>
			</p>

			For general settings of the generated image, see the "General Plot
			Options" Tab.
		</intro>

		<tab name="Options">

			<option name="Categorical column">A categorical column (String, Integer, Boolean)
				which forms the x-axis categories
			</option>
			<option name="Keep categories in order of input">If checked, then the categories appear on the
				x-axis in the order they are first encountered in the input table.
				Otherwise, they are sorted into their natural ordering
			</option>
			<option name="Data (Y-Axis) Values">The column(s) containing the series datapoints
			</option>
			<option name="Show mean">Should the mean be included on the plot (as an
				open circle)?
			</option>
			<option name="Mean size">The size that the mean should be shown at
			</option>
			<option name="Show median">Should the median be included on the plot?
			</option>
			<option name="Show notch">Should the notch be shown on the plot?</option>
			<option name="Notch size">The proportion of the width of the box by which
				each notch is indented
			</option>
			<option name="Horizontal boxes">Plot is rotated so boxes are horizontal</option>
			<option name="Show legend">Should a legend be included. Legend will show
				series colours and category colours as appropriate
			</option>

			<option name="Ensure outliers on plot">Without this setting, extreme outliers may be
				missed off the extremes of the plot. Checking this setting ensures
				the axes are scaled to ensure that all outliers appear
			</option>
			<option name="Line Width">The width (thickness) of the whisker lines and
				box outlines
			</option>
			<option name="Whisker Width">The width of the tails of the whiskers, relative
				to the width of the box
			</option>
			<option name="Outlier size">The size of the outliers</option>
			<option name="Extreme Outlier size">The size of the extreme outliers</option>
			<option name="Default outline colour">The colour used for lines when no other colour is
				specified by table colour models
			</option>
			<option name="Default fill colour">The colour used for the box fills when no other
				colou is specified by table colour models
			</option>
		</tab>
		<tab name="General Plot Options">
			<option name="Type of Image"> The type of the created image can either be png
				or svg. PNGs are mostly smaller, SVGs provide details about plot and
				the possibility to be changed individually.
			</option>
			<option name="Title of Graph"> The title of the graph shown above the generated
				image. If the title is not activated, no title will be shown.
			</option>
			<option name="Width of Image (in pixel)"> The width of the generated image, not the plot
				width.
			</option>
			<option name="Height of Image (in pixel)"> The height of the generated image, not the plot
				height.
			</option>
			<option name="Background Color">The color of the background of the image. Hence
				this color is used for the area behind and around the plot as well
				as behind potential axis and legends.
			</option>
			<option name="Plot Background Color">The color of the background of the plot. Hence
				this color is used for the empty space in a plot.
			</option>
			<option name="Plot Background Alpha">The transparency of the plot background can be
				modified using an additional alpha value. An alpha value of 1 does
				not change the background transparency. Decreasing the alpha value
				will increase the plot background transparency.
			</option>
			<option name="Scale Font Size">Factor changes the font sizes within the
				JFreeChart view. A value greater the 1 increases all view fonts, a
				value between 0 and 1 decrease them.
			</option>
		</tab>
	</fullDescription>

	<ports>
		<inPort
			index="0"
			name="Data table">Data table with at least one categorical
			column and one numerical
			column
		</inPort>
		<inPort
			index="1"
			name="Series Colours">Optional table with series colours - see
			above for further
			details
		</inPort>
		<outPort
			index="0"
			name="Image">The image of the plot (SVG or PNG)
		</outPort>

	</ports>
	<views>
		<view
			index="0"
			name="Boxplot">
			Boxplot views of the input data
		</view>
	</views>

</knimeNode>
