<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="./fvvalifswitch.png" type="Manipulator"
	xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v2.8" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v2.8 http://knime.org/node/v2.8.xsd">
	<name>IF Switch (Flow Variable Value)</name>

	<shortDescription>
        This node provides an IF switch which selects the active port based on the comparison of a flow variable with
        a user-entered value.  The comparison method can also be selected.
    </shortDescription>

	<fullDescription>
		<intro><p>This node provides an IF switch which selects the active port based on the comparison of a flow variable with
        a user-entered value.  The comparison method can also be selected.  It can be considered to be broadly similar in function
        to the Java Snippet IF Switch node in the core KNIME implementation, and provides an exact analogue of the equivalent flow 
        variable flow control node.</p>
        <p>If numeric variables (double or integer types) are selected, the node will attempt to process the user-entered value
        as a number.  If this cannot be done, then the node will not be executable.  An empty string will not be interpreted as a numeric value.  
        Note that integers can not be compared
        with values where a '.' is present, so '1.0' cannot be interpreted, but '1' can.</p>
        <p>For doubles, a threshold is specified in the dialogue.  If the variable is within this threshold of the comparison value
        it will be considered to be equal to it (Applies to =, !=, &gt;= and &lt;= comparisons).</p>
        <p>String comparisons are '<a href="http>//en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lexicographical_order">lexicographical</a>' - i.e. 
        the sorting order mirrors that in which the strings would be expected to appear in a dictionary.</p>
        <p>If the comparison is considered to be 'true', then the top port will be active, otherwise the bottom port
        will be active</p>		
		
			<p>This node was developed by <a href="http://www.vernalis-research.com/">Vernalis Research</a>. 
			For feedback and more information, please contact <a href="mailto:knime@vernalis.com">
			knime@vernalis.com</a></p>
		</intro>


		<option name="Flow variable selection (un-named in dialogue)">Select from the available flow variables</option>
		<option name="Comparison operator selection (un-named in dialogue)">Select the required comparison operation</option>
		<option name="Comparison value (un-named in dialogue)">Enter a value</option>
		<option name="Ignore case">Ignore the case (String comparisons only)</option>
		<option name="Ignore leading/trailing whitespace">Ignore leading / trailing white-space characters (String 
		comparisons only)</option>
		<option name="Equality tolerance">The maximum difference between double values within 
		which they will still be considered to be equal</option>

		
	</fullDescription>

	<ports>
		<inPort index="0" name="Input port">Input port</inPort>
		<outPort index="0" name="true">Active port if comparison is true</outPort>
		<outPort index="1" name="false">Active port if comparison is false</outPort>
	</ports>

</knimeNode>
