<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!--
  Copyright (c) 2018, Vernalis (R&D) Ltd
   This program is free software; you can redistribute it and/or modify it 
   under the terms of the GNU General Public License, Version 3, as 
   published by the Free Software Foundation.
   
   This program is distributed in the hope that it will be useful, but 
   WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY; without even the implied warranty of 
   MERCHANTABILITY or FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE. 
   See the GNU General Public License for more details.
    
   You should have received a copy of the GNU General Public License
   along with this program; if not, see <http://www.gnu.org/licenses>
-->
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode>
<knimeNode
	icon="./injectProps.png"
	type="Manipulator"
	xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v2.8"
	xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v2.10 http://knime.org/node/v2.10.xsd">
	<name>Inject Column Properties</name>

	<shortDescription>
		This node inserts column properties from a second
		input table into the columns from the first input table
	</shortDescription>

	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
			<p>
				This node adds column properties from a table of new properties to
				the existing input table. The second input table provides the new
				column properties, and must have the first three columns as String
				columns with the names
				<ol>
					<li>Column Name</li>
					<li>Property Name</li>
					<li>Property Value</li>
				</ol>
				Existing properties are optionally overwritten or retained according
				to the node settings
			</p>
			<p>
				Note:
				<ol>
					<li>It is not possible to change the order of properties for an
						individual column in the column properties table
					</li>
					<li>All column properties are stored as text/String values
						regardless of what they represent
					</li>
					<li>If the same column name / property name occurs more than once
						in the input table, only the last value will be applied to the
						output table
					</li>
				</ol>
			</p>

			<p>
				This node was developed by
				<a href="http://www.vernalis-research.com/">Vernalis Research (Cambridge, UK)</a>
				.
				For feedback and more information, please contact
				<a href="mailto:knime@vernalis.com">knime@vernalis.com</a>
			</p>
		</intro>


		<option name="Clear existing properties">Should existing properties from the incoming table
			be cleared prior to applying the new properties?
		</option>
		<option name="Apply to all columns">If existing properties are cleared, should they be
			cleared from all incoming columns, or only those with new properties?
		</option>
		<option name="Overwrite duplicate properties">If existing properties are being retained, should
			a new value for an existing property overwrite the existing value?
		</option>
		<option name="Use incoming table spec during configure">Most of the time, using the incoming table spec
			for the output table during the node configuration will not cause any
			problems, and allow downstream nodes to be configured. In this case,
			the output will at configure have the incoming properties regardless
			of the node settings. If this causes a problem, then uncheck this
			option, in which case a table spec will not be available at the
			output until the node is executed
		</option>
		

	</fullDescription>

	<ports>
		<inPort
			index="0"
			name="Input Table">Incoming data table to apply the properties to</inPort>
		<inPort
			index="1"
			name="Column Properties">The incoming table containing the properties. See above for
			detailed requirements. NB In KNIME, all properties are stored as text
		</inPort>
		<outPort
			index="0"
			name="Input Table with modified properties">The input table with modified column properties</outPort>
	</ports>

</knimeNode>
