<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./Smartsviewer_icon.png" type="Manipulator">
    <name>SMARTSViewer</name>
    
    <shortDescription>
        Retrieves a SMARTSViewer visualisation of a columns of SMARTS strings using the service at www.smartsviewer.de
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
        <intro>Provides a <a href="http://www.smartsview.de/">SMARTSviewer</a> visualisation
        of a column of SMARTs strings (SMARTS, Smiles or String cell types accepted as inputs)
        using the service provided by the University of Hamburg.  The node performs no validation
        of the SMARTs strings prior to sending to the webservice. For more detailed information 
        about the implementation see either the Help file at <a href="http://smartsview.zbh.uni-hamburg.de/smartsview/view">http://smartsview.zbh.uni-hamburg.de/smartsview/view</a>
        or the following reference: <br />
        K. Schomburg, H.-C. Ehrlich, K. Stierand, M.Rarey; 
        <a href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/ci100209a">From Structure Diagrams to Visual Chemical Patterns</a>, <i>J. Chem. Inf. Model.</i>, 2010, <b>50</b>, pp 1529-1535
		
		<p><i>
		Note that SMARTs strings are transferred to the remote server unencrypted, and the the server
        maintains an anonymous record of query SMARTs strings to aid future development.</i></p>
		<p>This node was developed by <a href="http://www.vernalis.com/">Vernalis (Cambridge, UK)</a>.
		For feedback and more information, please contact <a href="mailto:knime@vernalis.com">knime@vernalis.com</a>
		</p>
        </intro>
        
        
        <option name="Select a column contaning the SMARTs Strings">Select a column containing SMARTs strings for visualsation.  Accepted column
        types are SMARTS, Smiles and String.  No SMARTS validation is carried out prior to sending to the remote server, which will
        return a blank image for invalid SMARTS strings</option>
        <option name="Select legend type">Choose the desired legend type: Dynamic - detailed text description of each atom and bond;
         Static - short description of how each symbol is depicted in the visualisation</option>
        <option name="Select Visualisation modus">Element symbols uses text representation of the element symbols in the depiction</option>
        
        <!-- possibly more options that can also be grouped by tabs -->
        <!--
        <tab name="Standard Options">
            <option name="short name of first option (like in the dialog)">description of first option</option>
            <option name="short name of second option (like in the dialog)">description of second option</option>
        </tab>
        <tab name="Advanced Options">
            <option name="short name of first advanced option (like in the dialog)">description of first advanced option</option>
        </tab>
        -->
    </fullDescription>
    
    <ports>
        <inPort index="0" name="In port 0">Input port containing a column of SMARTS strings, either as String, SMARTS or Smiles format</inPort>
        <!-- possibly more input ports here-->
        <outPort index="0" name="Appended SMARTSViewer Renderings">The input table with the SMARTSViewer representations appended as a PNG column</outPort>
        <!-- possibly more output ports here-->
    </ports>    
    <!--<views>
        <view index="0" name="name of first view">Description of first view...</view>
    </views>-->
</knimeNode>
