<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="./FlowControlfvvalifswitch_16x16.png" type="Manipulator"
	xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v3.1" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v3.1 http://knime.org/node/v3.1.xsd" deprecated="true">
	<name>Flow Variable IF Switch (Flow Variable Value)</name>

	<shortDescription>
        This node provides an IF switch which selects the active port based on the comparison of a flow variable with
        a user-entered value.  The comparison method can also be selected.
    </shortDescription>

	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
			<p>This node provides an IF switch which selects the active port
				based on the comparison of a flow variable with
				a user-entered value. The comparison method can also be selected. It
				can be considered to be broadly similar in function
				to the Java Snippet IF Switch node in the core KNIME implementation.
			</p>
			<p>If numeric variables (double or integer types) are selected, the
				node will attempt to process the user-entered value
				as a number. If this cannot be done, then the node will not be
				executable. An empty string will not be interpreted as a numeric
				value.
				Note that integers can not be compared
				with values where a '.' is present, so '1.0' cannot be interpreted, but
				'1' can.
			</p>
			<p>For doubles, a threshold is specified in the dialogue. If the
				variable is within this threshold of the comparison value
				it will be considered to be equal to it (Applies to =, !=, &gt;= and
				&lt;= comparisons).</p>
			<p>
				String comparisons are '
				<a href="http>//en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Lexicographical_order">lexicographical</a>
				' - i.e.
				the sorting order mirrors that in which the strings would be expected
				to appear in a dictionary.
			</p>
			<p>If the comparison is considered to be 'true', then the top port
				will be active, otherwise the bottom port
				will be active
			</p>

			<p>
				NOTE - Due to the way in which flow variables are handled within
				KNIME, no matter which
				the active branch, the flow variable values for any existing flow
				variables beyond the corresponding
				"end" node will be those at the top-most port of the "end" node. New
				variables created in any active branch will
				retain their correct values. If you need to change the value of existing
				variables, please either use
				a new flow variable, or use a
				<i>variable to tablerow</i>
				node before a conventional
				<i>End IF</i>
				node.
			</p>

			<p>This node was developed by <a href="http://www.vernalis-research.com/">Vernalis Research</a>. 
			For feedback and more information, please contact <a href="mailto:knime@vernalis.com">
			knime@vernalis.com</a></p>
		</intro>


		<option name="Flow variable selection (un-named in dialogue)">Select from the available flow variables</option>
		<option name="Comparison operator selection (un-named in dialogue)">Select the required comparison operation</option>
		<option name="Comparison value (un-named in dialogue)">Enter a value</option>
		<option name="Ignore case">Ignore the case (String comparisons only)</option>
		<option name="Ignore leading/trailing whitespace">Ignore leading / trailing white-space characters
			(String
			comparisons only)
		</option>
		<option name="Equality tolerance">The maximum difference between double values
			within
			which they will still be considered to be equal
		</option>


	</fullDescription>

	<ports>
		<inPort index="0" name="Input port">Input port containing flow variable with
			value to compare</inPort>
		<outPort index="0" name="true">Active port if comparison is true
		</outPort>
		<outPort index="1" name="false">Active port if comparison is false
		</outPort>
	</ports>

</knimeNode>
