<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="./Frag2MMP.png" type="Manipulator" deprecated="true"
	xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v2.8" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v2.8 http://knime.org/node/v2.8.xsd">
	<name>Fragments to MMPs</name>

	<shortDescription>
        This node generates matched molecular pairs (MMPs) from fragments generated using the Hussain and Rea algorithm
    </shortDescription>

	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
			<p>This node implements the Hussain and Rea algorithm for finding
				Matched Molecular Pairs in a dataset. The node takes an input table
				of fragments generated either by the MMP Molecule
				Fragment node and
				generates an output table of matched molecular
				pairs (MMPs)
			</p>
			<p>The node requires two SMILES input columns, representing the 'key'
				(unchanging atoms) and 'value', and a string column containing the
				ID. The node will attempt to
				auto-guess these column selections based
				on the default names for
				the columns output by the fragment node.
			</p>
			<p>Optionally, the user can specify that the table is pre-sorted by
				keys. If this option is selected, then the user can allow checking
				of the output for correct sorting, in which case, the node will fail
				if an earlier key is found again later in the table. This method
				uses less memory, as the entire input table does not have to be
				loaded into memory. For anything other than small datasets, the user
				is recommended to pre-sort the input table by key, and then use this
				setting.
			</p>
			<p>
				Any attachment point fingerprint(s) generated during fragmentation are
				passed through and attached to the appropriate transformations
			</p>
			<p>
				This node was developed by
				<a href="http://www.vernalis-research.com/">Vernalis Research</a>.
				For feedback and more information, please contact
				<a href="mailto:knime@vernalis.com">
					knime@vernalis.com
				</a>
			</p>
			<p>
				1.J. Hussain and C Rea, "
				<i>Computationally efficient algorithm to identify matched molecular pairs (MMPs) in large datasets</i>
				",
				<i>J. Chem. Inf. Model.</i>
				, 2010,
				<b>50</b>
				, 339-348 (DOI:
				<a href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/ci900450m">10.1021/ci900450m</a>
				).
			</p>
		</intro>

		<tab name="Options">
			<option name="Select the Fragment Key column">Select the column containing the fragment 'keys'
			</option>
			<option name="Keys are sorted">Use this option if the keys column is pre-sorted.
				See above for details
			</option>
			<option name="Check keys are sorted">It is strongly recommended to use this option if
				specifying that keys are pre-sorted, in order to avoid missing MMPs
				from the dataset if a sorting error has occurred.
			</option>
			<option name="Select the ID column">
				Select the column containing the parent molecule
				IDs
			</option>
			<option name="Select the Fragment Value column">Select the column containing the fragment
				'values'
			</option>
		</tab>

		<tab name="Output Settings">
			<option name="Remove Explicit H's from output">Explicit hydrogens will be removed from the
				output if selected
			</option>
			<option name="Show unchanging portion">A SMILES cell will be included showing the 'key'
				resulting in the fragmentation pattern
			</option>
			<option name="Show number of changing atoms">The number of heavy atoms (not including 'A', the
				attachment point) will be included for Left and Right fragments
			</option>
			<option name="Show ratio of constant / changing heavy atoms">The ratio of constant / changing heavy atoms (not
				including 'A', the attachment point) will be included for Left and
				Right fragments
			</option>
			<option name="Show reverse-direction transforms">The transformations will be duplicated in the
				'reverse' direction, e.g. A-->B and B-->A
			</option>
			<option name="Include Reactions SMARTS">In addition to the SMIRKS representation of the
				transformation, the transform is shown in an rSMARTS representation
				with atom mappings. Using this option without the 'Track
				Connectivity' option selected will produce nonsense rSMARTS!
			</option>
		</tab>

	</fullDescription>

	<ports>
		<inPort index="0" name="Key-Value pairs">Fragmented molecule key-value pairs
		</inPort>
		<outPort index="0" name="MMP transforms">Matched pair transformations
		</outPort>

	</ports>

</knimeNode>
