<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode
	icon="./ePMCv1.png"
	type="Source">
	<name>European PubMed Central Advanced Search</name>

	<shortDescription>
		Node to run a reference query on the European PubMed
		Central webservice
		and return the results as an XML table
	</shortDescription>

	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
			<p>
				This node re-creates the
				<a href="http://europepmc.org/advancesearch">
					advanced query interface</a>
				of European-PubMed Central. The options shown in the
				query dialog
				replicate those found on that page. For detailed help see
				the
				advanced query
				page and also the
				<a href="http://europepmc.org/Help">help page</a>
			</p>
			<p>
				The node uses the RESTful query webservice, documented at
				<a href="http://europepmc.org/RestfulWebService#search">
					http://europepmc.org/RestfulWebService#search</a>
				. In addition to the query options,
				a 'Test' button is provided which
				shows the number of hits and the
				query as interpreted
				by the
				webservice.
			</p>
			<p>
				The node returns a single column of query results as XML cells - one
				row per result.
				The result fields can be accessed using the KNIME XML
				XPath node. A
				full list of fields
				is provided in the
				<a
					href="http://europepmc.org/docs/EBI_Europe_PMC_Web_Service_301_Reference.pdf">
					SOAP webservices guide</a>
			</p>
			<p>The Flow Variable port gives the query type (idlist, lite, core),
				hit count, page count, query string, query as parsed by European
				PubMed Central, and the URL of the first query page. At present, the
				flow variable output is not available if the node is run in
				streaming mode.
			</p>
			<p>
				This node was developed by
				<a href="http://www.vernalis.com">Vernalis</a>
				, who have no connection with European PubMed.
				Problems with the data
				should be reported directly to European PubMed
				Central. Vernalis
				accepts no responsibility for
				third party data. For further help with
				the node, contact
				<a href="mailto:knime@vernalis.com">
					knime@vernalis.com</a>
			</p>
		</intro>


		<option name="ePub Med Central Advanced Query">Query form mirroring that at the Advanced Query
			form at the European PubMed Central (see above)
		</option>
		<option name="General query">Any of the query tags from the European PubMed
			Central help page can be added here. Also, the query string flow
			variable output by the node
			will reproduce the query if used to set
			this parameter. (Which can then
			be combined with other query options
			in the remainder of the form)
		</option>
		<option name="Select the query type">idlist (a list of hit IDs), lite (main publication
			details) or core (extensive details) - see European PubMed Central
			website for details
		</option>
		<option name="Select the sort order">Sort by date or by relevance</option>
		<option name="Page size">This is the number of hits that will be return by
			each webservice call. Larger values will require fewer calls, but are
			more likely to fail (at which point the node will retry at increasing
			intervals)
		</option>
		<option name="Optional email address for EBI Webservices mailing list">If you supply an email address here, it will be
			added to the EBI ePMC webservices mailing list (see the webstie for
			details). If you do not wish to be added, leave this field blank. NB
			Vernalis will NOT see your email address, it will simply be went to
			the EBI service call. Vernalis will not email you about updates to
			the node. If you wish to contact Vernalis about the node, please use
			the contact details below
		</option>
		<option name="Test Query">Test the query. The number of hits will be shorn
			adjacent to the button, and the query as parsed by European PubMed
			Central will show in the box below
		</option>
		<option name="Clear">Clear the Test query boxes. NB Does not clear the
			query fields!
		</option>

	</fullDescription>

	<ports>
		<outPort
			index="0"
			name="Results">Single XML column of query results</outPort>
		<outPort
			index="1"
			name="Parameters">Flow variable port has a number of parameters relating to the
			query added
		</outPort>
	</ports>

</knimeNode>
