<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode>
<!--
	Copyright (c) 2018, Vernalis (R&D) Ltd
	This program is free software; you can redistribute it and/or modify it
	under the terms of the GNU General Public License, Version 3, as
	published by the Free Software Foundation.

	This program is distributed in the hope that it will be useful, but
	WITHOUT ANY WARRANTY; without even the implied warranty of
	MERCHANTABILITY or FITNESS FOR A PARTICULAR PURPOSE.
	See the GNU General Public License for more details.

	You should have received a copy of the GNU General Public License
	along with this program; if not, see <http://www.gnu.org/licenses>
-->
<knimeNode
	icon="amixpeaks.png"
	type="Source"
	xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v3.1"
	xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v3.1 http://knime.org/node/v3.1.xsd">
	<name>Load Bruker AMIX Peaklist Files</name>

	<shortDescription>
		Node to load one or more Bruker AMIX Peaklist files
		into a KNIME Table
	</shortDescription>

	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
			<p>Each Peaklist file is loaded and parsed such that one output
				row of
				the table contains the peaklist for 1 spectrum. Files may be a mix
				of 1D and 2D spectra
			</p>
			<p>
				The output table contains:
				<ul>
					<li>The single spectrum peaklist file - ie the portion of the input
						file for a single spectrum
					</li>
					<li>Title - Assigned by AMIX, not the spectrum title</li>
					<li>Date - The date the peaklist was exported from AMIX,
						not the
						date the spectrum was obtained
					</li>
					<li>User - The user on the machine AMIX was running on, not the
						user
						acquiring the spectrum
					</li>
					<li>Host - The machine AMIX was running on, not the spectrometer
					</li>
					<li>Spectrum - the path to the spectrum data loaded to AMIX</li>
					<li>w1 - A list of the w1 frequencies ('w' in the case of 1D
						spectra are in this column)</li>
					<li>w2 - A list of the w2 frequencies, for 2D spectra, or missing
						values</li>
					<li>Intensity - A list of the peak intensities</li>
					<li>Volume - A list of the peak volumes</li>
					<li>Annotation - A list of the peak annotations (If there are no
						annotations, this will contain a missing value cell)
					</li>
				</ul>
			</p>
			<p>
				The lists can be correctly resolved using an
				<tt>Ungroup</tt>
				node
			</p>
			<p>
				This node was developed by
				<a href="https://www.vernalis.com/">Vernalis Research</a>
				.
				For feedback and more information, please contact
				<a href="mailto:knime@vernalis.com">
					knime@vernalis.com
				</a>
			</p>
		</intro>


		<option name="Select files">Use the 'Browse...' and 'Add from history' buttons
			to add all the files to be included in the table. Alternatively, a
			flow variable can be specified, containing one or more filenames
			separated by ';'. The latest added file(s) will be selected. If no
			files are highlighted in the 'Selected files' box, then the
			'Browse...' button opens a new file browser window in the default
			location; otherwise, the file browser opens in the last highlighted
			file's location.
		</option>
		<option name="Select file encoding">Select the file encoding. 'Guess' will attempt to
			assign it based on the connectin property of the URL, the
			content-type, and the Byte-Order Mark (BOM). UTF-8 will be used if no
			other encoding is identified
		</option>
		<option name="Include paths in output table">Include the full file path and URLs as columns in
			the output table
		</option>
		<option name="Include filename in Row IDs">The filename will be included in the Row ID
			(duplicated will be suffixed with '_n', where n is an index starting
			at 0). Otherwise, the Row IDs will be in the format 'Row_n', with an
			an index starting at 0
		</option>
		<option name="Include filenames in output table">Include the filename as a column in the output
			table</option>
		<option name="Newline output">The newline character(s) to be used in the cell
			containing the full peaklist file for the individual spectrum.
			'System' will dynamically use the the newline of the system the node
			is executed on (the current value for this is shown in the dialog,
			but on another system, the local value will be used). 'Preserve
			incoming' will look in the first 65535 characters of the file for the
			first linebreak ('\r\n' or '\n') and use that</option>
	</fullDescription>

	<ports>
		<inPort
			index="0"
			name="Flow variables">Optional flow variables containing file path(s)</inPort>
		<outPort
			index="0"
			name="AMIX Peaks list">Parsed content of the loaded files
		</outPort>

	</ports>

</knimeNode>
