<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<knimeNode
	icon="./Frag2MMP.png"
	type="Manipulator"
	xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v3.1"
	xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v3.1 http://knime.org/node/v3.1.xsd">
	<name>Fragments to MMPs</name>

	<shortDescription>
        This node generates matched molecular pairs (MMPs) from fragments generated using the Hussain and Rea algorithm
    </shortDescription>

	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
			<p>This node implements the Hussain and Rea algorithm for finding
				Matched Molecular Pairs in a dataset. The node takes an input table
				of fragments generated by the MMP Molecule
				Fragment nodes and
				generates an output table of matched molecular
				pairs (MMPs)
			</p>
			<p>The node requires two SMILES input columns, representing the 'key'
				(unchanging atoms) and 'value', and a string column containing the
				ID. The node will attempt to
				auto-guess these column selections based
				on the default names for
				the columns output by the fragment node.
			</p>
			<p>The input table can contain fragmentations from differing numbers
				of cuts, in which case this will be reflected in the output table.
			</p>
			<p>The table will be pre-sorted by key followed by value during
				execution, unless the 'Incoming table is sorted by Keys and Values?'
				option is selected. If this option is selected and correct sorting
				is not applied, then pairs may be missed (incorrect keys sorting) or
				non-canonical in their direction (incorrect values sorting)
			</p>
			<p>Incoming columns can be passed through unchanged (Left, Right or
				both), numeric columns (Integer, Long, Double and Complex
				Number) can
				have differences (L - R or R - L) and ratios (Double only)
				calculated (L / R or R / L)
			</p>
			<p>
				Transforms can be filtered based on the Value Attachment point graph
				distance calculated during fragmentation using a number of options
				<ul>
					<li>None - No filtering</li>
					<li>Max total graph distance change - the sum of all graph distance
						changes
					</li>
					<li>Max single graph distance change - the maximum tolerated change
						in any single distance
					</li>
					<li>Tanimoto - the vector Tanimoto similarity</li>
					<li>Dice - the vector Dice similarity</li>
					<li>Cosine - the vector Cosine similarity</li>
					<li>Euclidean - the vector Euclidean distance</li>
					<li>Hamming - the vector Hamming (Manhattan or City-block) distance
					</li>
					<li>Soergel - the vector Soergel distance</li>
				</ul>
				Filtering can also be performed based on the change in heavy atom
				count during the transformation
			</p>
			<p>
				This node was developed by
				<a href="https://www.vernalis.com/">Vernalis Research</a>
				.
				For feedback and more information, please contact
				<a href="mailto:knime@vernalis.com">
					knime@vernalis.com
				</a>
			</p>
			<p>
				1.J. Hussain and C Rea, "
				<i>Computationally efficient algorithm to identify matched molecular pairs (MMPs) in large datasets</i>
				",
				<i>J. Chem. Inf. Model.</i>
				, 2010,
				<b>50</b>
				, 339-348 (DOI:
				<a href="http://dx.doi.org/10.1021/ci900450m">10.1021/ci900450m</a>
				).
			</p>
		</intro>

		<tab name="Options">
			<option name="Select the Fragment Key column">Select the column containing the fragment 'keys'
			</option>
			<option name="Select the Fragment Value column">Select the column containing the fragment
				'values'
			</option>
			<option name="Incoming table is sorted by Keys and Values?">Use this option if the input table is pre-sorted
				by 'keys', then by 'values'.
				See above for details
			</option>
			<option name="Select the ID column">
				Select the column containing the parent molecule
				IDs
			</option>
			<option name="Allow self-transforms">Allows two regioisomeric fragmentations of an
				input molecule resulting in identical keys but differing values to
				provide a 'self-transform' between the fragmentations
			</option>
			<option name="Filter by HAC Change">Should the transform be filtered by delta HAC? NB
				This is asymmetric so the 'Show reverse-direction transforms' option
				will not show pairs in some cases, e.g. if the range is set from -2
				to +4 then a transform losing 3 heavy atoms in the forwards
				direction will only show in the reverse direction
			</option>
			<option name="HAC Change Range">The range of acceptable HAC changes</option>
			<option name="Show HAC change in output table">Should the HAC change be shown in the output
				table
			</option>
			<option name="Graph Distance Similarity">If a fragmentation value attachment point graph
				distance fingerprint
				was calculated during fragmentation, than that
				can be used to restrict the transforms generated according to
				various similarity or disance cut-off functions (see above)
			</option>
			<option name="Cutoff (Double)">The cutoff threshold for doubles</option>
			<option name="Cutoff (Integer)">The cutoff threshold for integers</option>
			<option name="Graph Distance fingerint column">The column containing the counts fingerprint for
				the graph distances between attachment points
			</option>
			<option name="Include distance/similarity in output">Should the calculated graph distance or
				similarity be included in the output table
			</option>
		</tab>

		<tab name="Pass-through columns">
			<option name="Left Columns to pass through unchanged">The columns from the left molecule of the
				transform to pass through unchanged
			</option>
			<option name="Right Columns to pass through unchanged">The columns from the right molecule of the
				transform to pass through unchanged
			</option>
		</tab>

		<tab name="Difference columns">
			<option name="Left - Right">Those numeric (int, double, long, complex number)
				columns for which the L-R difference should be calculated
			</option>
			<option name="Right - Left">Those numeric (int, double, long, complex number)
				columns for which the R-L difference should be calculated
			</option>
		</tab>

		<tab name="Ratio columns">
			<option name="Left / Right">Those numeric double columns for which the L/R
				ratio should be calculated
			</option>
			<option name="Right - Left">Those numeric double columns for which the R/L
				ratio should be calculated
			</option>
		</tab>

		<tab name="Output Settings">
			<option name="Remove Explicit H's from output">Explicit hydrogens will be removed from the
				output if selected
			</option>
			<option name="Show unchanging portion">A SMILES cell will be included showing the 'key'
				resulting in the fragmentation pattern
			</option>
			<option name="Show number of changing atoms">The number of heavy atoms (not including 'A', the
				attachment point) will be included for Left and Right fragments
			</option>
			<option name="Show ratio of constant / changing heavy atoms">The ratio of constant / changing heavy atoms (not
				including 'A', the attachment point) will be included for Left and
				Right fragments
			</option>
			<option name="Show reverse-direction transforms">The transformations will be duplicated in the
				'reverse' direction, e.g. A-->B and B-->A
			</option>
			<option name="Include Reactions SMARTS">In addition to the SMIRKS representation of the
				transformation, the transform is shown in an rSMARTS representation
				with atom mappings
			</option>
			<option name="Require single acyclicly bonded attachment points">Should the reaction SMARTS explicitly require
				that the bonds to attachment point dummy atoms are all single,
				acyclic bonds ('-!@'), as this is what is allowed to break
			</option>
		</tab>

	</fullDescription>

	<ports>
		<inPort
			index="0"
			name="Key-Value pairs">Fragmented molecule key-value pairs
		</inPort>
		<outPort
			index="0"
			name="MMP transforms">Matched pair transformations
		</outPort>

	</ports>

</knimeNode>
