<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./colInsert.png" type="Manipulator">
	<name>Insert into List</name>

	<shortDescription>
		Adds cells from one or more columns to a specified
		position in a list column
	</shortDescription>

	<fullDescription>
		<intro>
			<p>This node adds the cells from one or more columns to a specified
				position within a collection column. Optionally, the
				selected columns
				can be removed from the output tables, and missing
				cells may be
				skipped or added.
			</p>
			<p>
				This node was developed by
				<a href="http://www.vernalis.com/">Vernalis (Cambridge, UK)</a>
				.
				For feedback and more information, please contact
				<a href="mailto:knime@vernalis.com">knime@vernalis.com</a>
			</p>
		</intro>

		<option name="Collection Column">The List column to insert into
		</option>
		<option name="Columns to append">The additional column(s) to insert. Only columns
			of the appropriate type for the selected collection will be shown
		</option>
		<option name="Remove appended columns">Should the columns selected to insert into the
			list be removed from the output table?
		</option>
		<option name="Insertion Index">The position in the list to insert the cells. 0 is
			before the first element. Negative indices are counted from the end
			of the list, so -1 is the position before the last element
		</option>
		<option name="Fail execution if index is out of bounds">The node will fail execution if the index is out
			of bounds, otherwise indices beyond the end of the list will add to
			the end of the list, and indices before the start of the list will
			add to the start</option>
		<option
			name="Treat missing collection cells as empty collections">A missing cell in the collection column will be left unchanged
			unless this option is selected, in which case a new list will be created containing only the
			inserted cells.
		</option>
		<option name="Don't add missing cells to collection">If this option is selected, missing cells in any
			inserted columns will be skipped
		</option>

	</fullDescription>

	<ports>
		<inPort index="0" name="List column">Table containing a List column and column(s) of cells to insert
		</inPort>
		<outPort index="0" name="Inserted Collection">Table containing the input table with
			selected columns inserted into the selected list column
		</outPort>
	</ports>

</knimeNode>
