<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<knimeNode icon="./LoopEndTimed.png" type="LoopEnd"
	xmlns="http://knime.org/node/v3.1" xmlns:xsi="http://www.w3.org/2001/XMLSchema-instance"
	xsi:schemaLocation="http://knime.org/node/v3.1 http://knime.org/node/v3.1.xsd">
	<name>Timed Loop End (3 port)</name>

	<shortDescription>
        Loop End node for timed loops, exposing unprocessed rows in the final port
    </shortDescription>

	<fullDescription>
		<intro>

			<p>Loop end node to partner with 'Run-to-time' and
				'Run-for-time' loop start nodes. Rows which were not
				processed before the loop execution finished as a result of
				the time setting of the loop start node are made available
				at the last output port. Flow variables with the last
				iteration counter and end time are exposed.
			</p>
			<p>
				This node was developed by
				<a href="http://www.vernalis-research.com/">Vernalis Research</a>
				.
				For feedback and more information, please contact
				<a href="mailto:knime@vernalis.com">
					knime@vernalis.com
				</a>
			</p>
		</intro>


			<option name="Row key policy">
		How should row keys, which must be unique, be
		generated in the output
		table? '
		<i>Generate new Row IDs</i>
		' generates new row IDs sequential in the form Row0, Row1 etc.; '
		<i>Unique Row IDs by appending suffix</i>
		' appends '_Iter#' and the iteration number to the incoming Row ID; '
		<i>Leave Row IDs unchanged</i>
		' leaves incoming Row IDs unchanged. Nodes which previously had
		'Uniquify Row IDs' set, will follow the second option
	</option>
	<option name="Add iteration column">Adds a column to the output table containing the
		iteration number, starting with 0
	</option>

	<option name="Ignore empty input tables">Selecting this option means the structure of empty
		input tables at the
		specified port will be ignored and they will not
		cause the node to fail
	</option>
	<option name="Allow changing column types">Tables in which the column names remain constant,
		but the types change between iterations will be allowed to pass. The
		type of columns changed will be the simplest type common to all input
		types. A message will be sent to the console explaining any failures
	</option>
	<option name="Allow changing table specs">Tables in which more complex changes to the table
		structure occur will be allowed to pass. This setting overrides the
		'Allow changing column types' setting. If this option is not set, a
		message will be sent to the console explaining any failures.
	</option>

	</fullDescription>

	<ports>
		<inPort index="0" name="In-Port 0">Loop data (0)</inPort>
		<inPort index="1" name="In-Port 1">Loop data (1)</inPort>
		<inPort index="2" name="In-Port 2">Loop data (2)</inPort>
		<outPort index="0" name="Processed Data (0)">Data processed in the loop (0)
		</outPort>
		<outPort index="1" name="Processed Data (1)">Data processed in the loop (1)
		</outPort>
		<outPort index="2" name="Processed Data (2)">Data processed in the loop (2)
		</outPort>
		<outPort index="3" name="Unprocessed Data">Data not processed in the loop due to
			time-out</outPort>
	</ports>
</knimeNode>
