<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE knimeNode PUBLIC "-//UNIKN//DTD KNIME Node 2.0//EN" "http://www.knime.org/Node.dtd">
<knimeNode icon="./pdb.ico" type="Source">
    <name>PDB Connector</name>
    
    <shortDescription>
        Source node to connect to RCSB PDB RESTful Web Services for advanced search and custom reporting.
    </shortDescription>
    
    <fullDescription>
        <intro><p>The <i>PDB Connector</i> source node provides connections to two RESTful Web Services for search and retrieval of information from the Protein Data Bank:
            <ul>
                <li>Advanced Search (http://www.rcsb.org/pdb/rest/search)</li>
                <li>Custom Report (http://www.rcsb.org/pdb/rest/customReport)</li>
            </ul>
        </p>
            <p>The user interface dialog options are designed to be a close mimic of the interactive web-based search and reporting options provided at
                <a href="http://www.pdb.org/pdb/search/advSearch.do">http://www.pdb.org/pdb/search/advSearch.do</a> and the user
                is encouraged to explore this resource for a full explanation of each search option.</p>
            <p>The node will make a number of retries at increasing delay intervals (0, 1, 5, 10, 30, 60, 300, 600 seconds) to download each block of report 
            	data during the second part of the execution (There is an additional delay, defaulting to 1 second, on each attempt, which can be adjusted by 
            	adding the line -Dknime.url.timeout= followed by a value in milliseconds - e.g. 5000 for 5 seconds to the knime.ini file).</p>
            <p>The <i>PDB Connector</i> node was developed by <a href="http://www.enspiral-discovery.com/">Enspiral Discovery</a> in collaboration with
                <a href="http://www.vernalis.com/">Vernalis (Cambridge, UK)</a>.
                For feedback and more information, please contact <a href="mailto:knime@vernalis.com">knime@vernalis.com</a>
                </p>
        </intro>
        <option name="Query Options">Master query tab. Use this tab to:
            <ul>
                <li>Control the (optional) sequence similarity filter, used to remove similar sequences from the search hits.</li>
                <li>Control the composite query logic (individual query options can be either ANDed or ORed together).</li>
                <li>Select the ligand image size to use in the generation of ligand image URLs (applies to Ligand Image field only).</li>
                <li>Clear all query options.</li>
                <li>Test the current query, with display of xml query string and result count.</li>
            </ul>
        </option>
        <option name="Report Options">Master reporting tab, to control the selection of custom report fields in OutPort1.
            <ul>
                <li>Use the dropdown menu to select from a number of predefined standard reports</li>
                <li>Or select Customizable Table to allow fine-grained selection of all custom report fields.</li>
                <li>Use Select All to initialise a Customizable Table with all report fields.</li>
                <li>Use Clear All to initialise a Customizable Table with no report fields.</li>
            </ul>
        </option>
        <option name="All other tabs">The remaining tabs display the individual query options within each search category.
            <ul>
                <li>To select a query option, either check the "Selected" checkbox or click anywhere on one of the individual query parameters.</li>
                <li>Enter the desired query parameters using the controls provided.</li>
                <li>To unselect a query option, uncheck the "Selected" checkbox.</li>
            </ul>
        </option>
        
    </fullDescription>
    
    <ports>
        <outPort index="0" name="PDB IDs">One-column table of PDB IDs that match query</outPort>
        <outPort index="1" name="Custom report table">Custom report fields.</outPort>
    </ports>    
</knimeNode>
